exercism.io 2019-07-09

# Privacy Policy | Exercism

Last Revised: April 2019

## Overview

Exercism (also referred to as exercism.io) is an online platform designed to help you improve your coding skills through practice and mentorship.

Our platform comprises of a web site is located at https://exercism.io (and associated subdomains) and a command line application (CLI).

We’re deeply committed to providing you with a safe and secure online platform for you to develop your software coding skills.

Exercism is run and managed by Exercism ("We", "Us"), a not-profit-company registered in the UK with Company Number 11733062. You might also want to read:

  * Our [Terms of Service](https://exercism.io/terms-of-service)
  * Our community [Code of Conduct](https://exercism.io/code-of-conduct)

Our approach to your privacy is very straightforward to understand.

  1. We do not collect more personal information than we need
  2. We will not share any data you give us (e.g. your email address) with other third parties
  3. We use tools like Google Analytics and Hotjar to understand how you use the site. The information from these tools is only used to make the site better.
  4. We try to give you as much control about what information you share. For instance, we offer facilities to have an anonymous handle/user name if you want, and we don't require you to create a public profile.

It is important to note that any code submissions you make and any feedback you give will be made **publicly** available under a Creative Commons license. However, using our privacy tools, you can decide if you want this content to be identifiably linked to you.

## The information we collect

### Information collected during account registration

During registration we collect some information about you, such as your name and email address. If you choose to sign up with a 3rd Party (e.g. GitHub OAuth) we will capture your name and email address from that service.

During sign-up you will also be asked to create a **Handle** , which will act as a username for any content you share on the site. There is no requirement for your Handle to be personally identifiable.

We use your name and email to send you notifications and updates (if you choose receive them) and any important Platform notices.

### Information we collect while you use our online Services

We may collect usage information about your use of our Service, such as the number of problems you have attempted, the number of videos you have viewed, and the amount of time spent to complete a problem. This enables us to better tailor educational experiences that are most appropriate for you.

This information may include:

  * The URLs of the page you are visiting
  * Some information about your browser's version and operating system
  * Information about your location (based on your IP address)

We use a number of 3rd party tools/services to collect this information, you can get information about them (including how to opt-out) of these services by visiting the following pages.

  * Google analytics: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
  * Hotjar: https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out

### GDPR

The GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) is European legislation that governs how we process data originating from users from the EU. Exercism aims to be GDPR compliant for all users, even those outside the EU and you therefore have some important rights applicable to our Platform.

  1. Your Right to be Informed - This Privacy Policy details who we are, what we collect, and what we use it for.

  2. Right of access - At any time you can review the information on your profile and update or change it. Through the exercism.io website you can view all your solutions.

  3. Right of portability - We can provide you with a copy of your personal data in a machine readable format. Please contact privacy@exercism.io for more information.

  4. Right to Erasure - We can remove your personal data from our systems so that you can no longer be personally identified to your solutions. Please contact privacy@exercism.io for more information.

It is important to note that any certain content solutions (including, but not limited to, problem **Solutions** and Mentor's feedback) are transferred to us under a non-revokable license and therefore cannot be deleted from the Platform.

### Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. The table below explains the cookies we use and why.

The sites https://exercism.io and https://teams.exercism.io use the following cookies

Cookie | Scope | Purpose  
---|---|---  
_exercism_session | *.exercism.io | manages your signed-in session on our web sites  
_ga | *.exercism.io | Google Analytics  
_gid | *.exercism.io | Google Analytics  
_hj | *.exercism.io | Hotjar cookies are prefixed with _hj - for more information see https://help.hotjar.com/hc/en-us/articles/115011789248-Hotjar-Cookies  
  
Other cookies may be set when you sign in through a 3rd Party (such as GitHub).

## How we use the information we've collected

To understand, improve, and develop our Platform and associated services. As detailed in our values, we aim to build a **positive and caring community** to help people **improve their programming skills**. In support of these aims, we may use the data we collect to improve the quality of our Users' learning and feedback. This may include performing data analysis on anonymised datasets.

## Sharing and transferring data

We do not rent or sell any Personal Information that we collect with third parties.

If you choose to publish personal information on our Platform (such as, for instance, your name on a public profile page), you will remain responsible and in control of that information. You should _NOT_ include personal information in your code solutions or feedback comments.
